All right, 5.3 customer awareness.
So this is, uh, a bonus module, uh, because I, I,
I feel like over the years I've realized there's different levels of awareness
as well as sophistication. Um,
and as a, as a video editor, as a video creative,
you need to know where the customer's awareness is in the funnel, uh,
so that you can provide a better message or better creative that suits them
where they're at in the buyer journey. Okay? Uh,
this is typical marketing 1 0 1, uh, in terms of the, the funnels,
but I wanna break it down for you in terms of going on a date.
All right, so you have awareness. Consider that's the top of funnel, right?
They don't know you.
You have to create awareness for yourself and for the product. Next,
you have consideration, I will consider buying the product.
And then number three, you have conversion,
which obviously is when they buy the product. And then if the product works,
then they're gonna be loyal to your brand, and then from there,
they're gonna be an advocate for your brand. So it's that whole,
whole process for Jenny, all right? Where she went from,
I'm not sure if this is gonna work to, all right,
I'm gonna tell my friends about it. So let me break this down for you.
If you were to date someone, because it's the same process here, okay?
Number one, who the f**k are you? You know,
if you just go up to somebody and be like, Hey, try this thing. They be like,
get up. What? Like, or if they, if you ask them to,
to go home with you and be like, who the f**k are you? Like, don't tell me.
Don't ask me that. I don't even know you. After you get to conversation,
they're gonna be, all right, I'm interested. What's up? Let's go on a date.
Okay? So in this consideration phase, you're gonna get to know each other.
You're gonna build trust, you're gonna build rapport. And then, you know, the,
the time comes where you've had enough, you know, tension and, and,
um, chemistry, and you're like, all right, let's take this back to my place.
And, you know, she goes, or he goes, yes, let's do it. Okay?
And that's when boom, you score, you get the conversion, you're stoked,
and then you're in that place for a little bit, right? Uh,
and then you start to build loyalty for each other. And, um, you know,
one of you says, I only wanna see you. I wanna make this exclusive.
You become loyal to each other. Uh, and once you become loyal to each other,
you're official, right? And then you start to advocate for each other.
You've gotta go meet my boyfriend, you've gotta meet my girlfriend.
You start introducing everyone to your, to your, to your new partner in life,
right? The same thing with the brand. And, um, and,
and that's how it's done online, and that's how it's done for anything
is there is a trust that needs to be built.
There is an awareness that needs to get started, but that ascension,
that journey, once you've gained someone's loyalty and advocacy,
you've had them for life. And so I believe that's, that's the,
the most challenging thing these days, especially, uh, in,
in the marketing direct response world, is we're just going for the conversions,
uh, as, as, as, as much as possible.
But when you can build loyalty and advocacy is when you build a mega,
mega brand. Think of Apple, right?
Think of these other companies where you've got people who are just, who,
who won't go anywhere else but, but them, you know,
that's when you built a moat around your brand.
Okay? So in this one, I want to just kind of break down Tofu, mofu, and bofu.
Top of funnel, middle of funnel, bottom of funnel. Same concept here,
but this is more of the terminology we use in the ad world. Um,
obviously create awareness. Uh, in, in, in the top of funnel,
in the middle funnel,
people will evaluate and see if you are the better option or if you're the best
option. Bottle funnel, bottom of funnel. This is when you know,
you wanna just like get, they're already a aware of you, they've evaluated you,
and this is where you get them to convert. Okay? This is the hot moment.
This is, this is when you got a hot buyer on the right side,
you have potential video ad styles,
depending on the funnel and the funnel stage that someone's at. So if they're,
if it's a top funnel ad, you're gonna be showing them problem solution videos.
You're gonna be showing them viral mashups, anchor videos.
You're really going to get their attention and educate them on what your product
does when, what problem it solves, right?
Once you've established that, okay,
next you're gonna put that customer into the middle of funnel,
now they know you, now they've clicked on you, they're aware of your brand.
This is where you're gonna throw u g c mashups testimonials,
maybe informational videos or articles,
us versus them branded videos to really, uh,
I would say fill their, fill their feeds with, with your brand, because you,
you, you're now present in their subconscious, they're present on their minds.
So you want, you wanna close that gap.
You wanna build that trust as fast as possible. And lastly,
if they haven't converted by now, you know, they're very, they've,
they're very much deeply into the funnel. Maybe they've,
they've added to heart at this point. You know,
you just want to get them to move forward. Discount, discount ads, promo videos,
testimonials with a discount or some sort of offer us versus them with an offer.
This is where you include a 55% discount. And I'll show you some examples.
So as they begin to become more familiarized with your,
your brand and, and the product and who you are as a company,
you know, you start want to narrowing the potentials, it's like less salesy.
Or maybe you can do like salesy, but like, okay, now just click and buy.
Okay?
So here are three different examples of top funnel ad middle funnel ad
and bottom of funnel ad. This is, uh, one of our clients, SSY.
We've worked with them for a very long time.
And you can see here in this example,
I dunno if you can hear this, but you can see the, the example here,
the hook, okay?
This is a, this is a top of funnel ad. All right?
So she doesn't mention anything about the,
the pillow until eight seconds in. Okay?
So she's starting with the hook, she's starting with the pain point.
She's starting with the before and after,
um,
years to my appearance. Um,
boom. Okay. So as you can tell in that top of funnel ad,
they did not introduce the product until eight seconds in this submittal funnel
ad, and, oh,
do I not have it? All right,
I'm gonna have to post it later on. But, um,
basically from here, all right,
you have the top of funnel ad. Who the f are you? I don't know you. Okay?
Now I know what you are. Middle of funnel ad. Okay,
you're leading with the product. All right, I'm interested. And then lastly,
bottom of funnel ad, you've got 55% off. You've got social proof in there.
Let's go person's. All right. All right, let's do it. I'm, I've,
I've seen enough of you guys.
It always depends on the product and audience and how much educating,
educating how much educating it requires to make a sale. All right?
This can vary from product to product, from offer to offer, from niche to niche.
This is one thing I wanted to break down was impulse versus consideration
products. Okay? Impulse buys. These are products that are affordable.
The price points are typically under, you know, $30 or so. Um,
versus longer buy cycles, which take more consideration.
Product that is 50 to a hundred dollars or more. And, uh,
people need to see if it's worth purchasing,
impulse buys products solve a quick problem versus longer buying or
consideration buys. They solve a specific problem.
An impulse buy products doesn't need much explaining versus, uh,
a consideration product is more sophisticated and requires a lot of additional
research. Impulse buys product is not oversize and easy to ship. And, uh,
versus product is product could require more shipping time and it,
uh, impulse by the product is good enough.
Quality versus consideration product is very high quality, okay?
In essence, what I'm trying to get at,
get at is there's tons of stuff on the internet and impulse buys are like the
king of Facebook ads. Alright? You see it, you're like, oh, that's stoked.
I'm stoked on that. All right, let me click buy, it's a drop shipping site.
You know, they get screwed 'cause it's like $20 cheap product. And, um,
you kind of burn through a lot of customers. But the longer buy cycles, the,
the products that are branded that are higher quality,
that have a higher price point, people are gonna do more research these days.
They're gonna look at other brands, they're gonna look at reviews,
they're gonna do more research, they're gonna think about it.
And so that's really where the whole funnel makes a big difference in
some of these, um, these, uh, these other products that are,
that I'll show you in a second. So on the left you have an impulse product.
You know, you've got your zucchini squash noodle maker and your little egg
egg boiler versus, and these, you can get, these are like 10, 15 bucks,
right?
Or you can get 'em for even cheaper if you go to the store versus you have a
cookware set for 400 bucks, right?
You're not gonna just impulse buy a $400 cookware set,
especially if you have one already. You,
you're gonna wanna know why this is $400 and what's in
it for me, you know, why would I spend 400 bucks? I mean,
obviously you've got social proof there, like a m**o 38,000 reviews,
but why is this gonna make me a better chef, right?
Why is this gonna make my food better?
I can just grab one of these dinky things and um, you know, get a solution.
But this is gonna take more consideration. Obviously.
On the left we have an impulse buy. We've got a little pop it phone case,
which is like nine bucks on Amazon versus this puffer case,
which is $65. Okay? What makes the Puffer case different? Why?
Why is it more, way more,
why is it six times the seven times more the price than just this typical phone
case? Well, there's a lot of different features and benefits that obviously, um,
this one entails versus this one
on the left you have a cleaning product, a spin made.
This is like an impulse buy. I'm sure this is like 1999, right?
You impulse products are, uh, seen on TV products are rarely,
above 20 bucks or 30 bucks. So you can see it's got, you know,
your typical seen on TV versus the consideration product,
which is a Dyson that, you know, obviously everyone has heard of a Dyson,
but this is a $350 product. You know, investing in one of these,
you have to think about it. You, you gotta do some reviews and be like, okay,
why is this one better than any of the other ones out there?
And so you're gonna take some time. You're not just gonna like,
impulse buy a $350 thing, or maybe you are, maybe you have that kind of money,
okay, impulse buy, I need it. I just need a a, a cooler,
I'm gonna the beach get this thing fast consideration. Buy, okay,
this thing is $850. I'm gonna think about this.
Why do I need a grizzly cooler for $850?
Why? Okay. Holds up to a hundred gallons when it's not hauling game 504, okay?
This is for a certain type of person, 60 pounds of ice.
Right now we're talking complete, specific,
very specific problem that it's trying to solve here. Big events, big hunts,
that's a specific type of consumer.